[
    {
        "question": "1. ¿A qué reino pertenecía Jaime I el Conquistador? <br>Jaime I the Conqueror ruled which kingdom?",
        "options": ["Aragon", "Castile-León", "Navarre"],
        "correctAnswer": "Aragon"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. Alfonso X el Sabio fundó ¿qué institución en Toledo? <br>Alfonso X 'the Wise' founded which school in Toledo?",
        "options": ["School of Translators", "University", "Royal Library"],
        "correctAnswer": "School of Translators"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Leonor López de Córdoba escribió una de las primeras ¿qué género en castellano? <br>Leonor López de Córdoba wrote one of the first what in Castilian?",
        "options": ["Autobiographies", "Novels", "Chronicles"],
        "correctAnswer": "Autobiographies"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. Abderramán III fue califa de Córdoba en el siglo… <br>Abd al-Rahman III was Caliph of Córdoba in the… century?",
        "options": ["10th", "8th", "9th"],
        "correctAnswer": "10th"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. Rodrigo Díaz de Vivar, ‘El Cid’, participó en luchas entre los reinos de… <br>The Cid fought between the kingdoms of…",
        "options": ["Castile and León", "Aragon and Navarre", "Granada and Seville"],
        "correctAnswer": "Castile and León"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. ¿Quién fue llamada “la Temeraria”? <br>Who was nicknamed “the Reckless”?",
        "options": ["Urraca I of León", "Eleanor of Córdoba", "Isabella I of Castile"],
        "correctAnswer": "Urraca I of León"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. Isabel I de Castilla y Fernando II de Aragón son conocidos como… <br>Isabella I and Ferdinand II are known as…",
        "options": ["The Catholic Monarchs", "The Christian Monarchs", "The Monarchs of Spain"],
        "correctAnswer": "The Catholic Monarchs"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. Aixa Bint Ahmed vivió en… <br>Aixa Bint Ahmed lived in…",
        "options": ["al-Andalus", "the Frankish Kingdom", "the Ottoman Caliphate"],
        "correctAnswer": "al-Andalus"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. ¿Quién rompió los lazos con Bagdad y proclamó al-Ándalus independiente? <br>Who broke ties with Baghdad and made al-Andalus independent?",
        "options": ["Abd al-Rahman III", "Almanzor", "Yusuf al-Mu’taman"],
        "correctAnswer": "Abd al-Rahman III"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. El matrimonio de Isabel y Fernando culminó la reconquista en… <br>Their marriage completed the Reconquista in…",
        "options": ["1492", "1485", "1479"],
        "correctAnswer": "1492"
    }
]
